<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pengyin's Corner (Posts about Linux)</title><link>https://pengyin-shan.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://pengyin-shan.com/categories/cat_linux.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2018 &lt;a href="mailto:pengyin.shan@outlook.com"&gt;Pengyin(Wendy) Shan&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 02:36:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Ubuntu Tips</title><link>https://pengyin-shan.com/posts/2015/Linux/ubuntu-tips/</link><dc:creator>Pengyin(Wendy) Shan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h4 id="java_home-errors"&gt;JAVA_HOME Errors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you final setting up &lt;code&gt;JAVA_HOME&lt;/code&gt;, you are supposed to set its path in two different places:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;~/.bashrc&lt;/code&gt;: You will see something like &lt;code&gt;export JAVA_HOME="/usr/lib/jvm/java-8-oracle"&lt;/code&gt;. Note &lt;em&gt;there are double quote sign in path, and there is no space between JAVA_HOME and path.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/etc/environment&lt;/code&gt; (Read Only): You will see something like &lt;code&gt;JAVA_HOME="/usr/lib/jvm/java-8-oracle". Note: *there is double quote for path, and there is no space between JAVA_HOME and path*.&lt;/code&gt; This is a read-only file and you need to be admin if you want to modify it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your &lt;code&gt;JAVA_HOME&lt;/code&gt; is not correctly set up, you may get following error in you Ubuntu:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="cannot-updateremove-software"&gt;Cannot Update/Remove Software&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find a official forum &lt;a href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/texinfo/+bug/993407"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my application, &lt;code&gt;xpad&lt;/code&gt;, cannot be removed because of this. When I run &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get remove xpad&lt;/code&gt;, a error message &lt;em&gt;install-info can fail to install due to syntax errors in /etc/environment&lt;/em&gt; appears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I check my &lt;code&gt;/etc/environment&lt;/code&gt; file. It turns out I had extra spaces in my JAVA_HOME, which cause the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if your &lt;code&gt;software updater&lt;/code&gt; in Ubuntu failed to download necessary packages, you may have a wrong setup of &lt;code&gt;JAVA_HOME&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="reminder-in-terminal"&gt;Reminder in Terminal&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you open terminal, you may get some error message such as &lt;code&gt;bash: export: ``/usr/lib/jvm/java-8-oracle': not a valid identifier&lt;/code&gt;. In this case, you need to check your ~/.bashrc file to make sure your JAVA_HOME format is correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you forget extact format of JAVA_HOME, you can open ~/.bashrc file using gedit, then following the format of other variables. You can varify by checking the color highlight of your JAVA_HOME line should be the same as all lines above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Linux</category><category>Ubuntu</category><guid>https://pengyin-shan.com/posts/2015/Linux/ubuntu-tips/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparation of Ubuntu14, Linux Mint17 Cinnamon and CentOS7, from a Linux Beginner</title><link>https://pengyin-shan.com/posts/2014/linux-comparation/</link><dc:creator>Pengyin(Wendy) Shan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On mid Dec, 2014, after thinking twice I decided to remove Windows 8.1 from my laptop (Dell XPS12). Instead I want to install linux on it. I'm a Linux &lt;em&gt;beginner&lt;/em&gt; and a web developer.
I want to record the reason I want to change to Linux and the comparation of three Linux system in this post. I may update this post later, since I'll learn more about Linux as time passes by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this may be useful for you, if you are a Linux beginner like me:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Till Dec 2014, The personal reason I want to transfer to Linux is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I know it can be very tough, I really want to learn linux/unix since I need to improve my system configuration skills. Plus working in commind line is kind of magical to me :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm tried of some "special" configuration that only windows have. Compared to using mouse to click all around screen, Linux can achieve functions in terminal with one line of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I think compared to Windows 7, Windows 8/8.1 has improved speed a lot, Linux(At least Ubuntu and Linux Mint) still runs faster than Windows 8.1. And most of them are lighter than Windows, allowing me to drop any program that I don't need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently have a mac mini that I'm very satisfied, but I don't think I should buy a macbook for now, basic on finicial reason. Plus my current laptop (Dell XPS12) is a very good one. It has lightweight and good hardware. The only trick part is it only has 120 SSD storage. For a Linux system it is good enough buy for Windows 8.1 it has some problem, since Windows itself is very large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't need Windows-Specialize software very offen. For example, I have a MSOffice2011 on my mac mini, which is good enough for me. As a web developer, I just need my favorite development tools/programs, such as &lt;code&gt;Eclispe&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;JDK Support&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;code&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/code&gt; and databases such as &lt;code&gt;MySQL&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;MongoDB&lt;/code&gt;. They all work weel on Linux, plus linux has very good support for Python and Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very personal reason is the display of my laptop has a little bit problem under Windows 8.1 (Or its configuration software). It has black shadow occationally. This problem disappears when I change to Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started from `Ubuntu14, to Linux Mint17 Cinnamon, to CentOS7, then back to Ubuntu14. I had a long and hard time configuring each system on my laptop and VirtualBox. During configuration process, I got a chance to learn these system's speciality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I choose these three system because compare to other Linux system, they are popular so as a beginner, I can easily get support when I have any problem during configuration process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I want to make a very simple comparation of these three systems, from a Linux beginner's perpective, with very &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ubuntu-14"&gt;Ubuntu 14&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="pros-for-me"&gt;Pros for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most familar. I started to use Ubuntu when I was in college based on class requirement, so I can start using it very fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfect community support. Ubuntu, since it is one of the most popular Linux system now, has great community support. Almost all questions I have can be answered. This is very important for Linux beginner like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great software support. Although Linux don't have a large software market like Windows or MacOS, Ubuntu has very outstanding software market that you can install with one-click. More important, among these three Linux systems, the installation process in Ubuntu has least probablity of rising problems. In most cases you don't need to change other files to isntall something. Even when you need to do extra configuration, there is always online guidence for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="cons-for-me"&gt;Cons for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost no compilance for a Linux beginner. This is a great system for you to get into the world of Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="linux-mint-17"&gt;Linux Mint 17&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="pros-for-me_1"&gt;Pros for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interface of Linux Mint is so similar to Windows 7/XP, so if you are a previous Windows user, you won't have too much trouble on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux Mint is based on Debian and Ubuntu, so it can almost run all software that Ubuntu has with one-click. Actually, I feel Linux Mint is almost the same as Ubuntu. So if you have a problem, the solution for Ubuntu should normally work in Linux Mint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may depends, but Linux Mint 17 runs faster on my laptop thatn Ubuntu 14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="cons-for-me_1"&gt;Cons for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm not very sure if this only happens in this version, but some programs in Ubuntu have problem in Linux Mint. For example, &lt;code&gt;Okular&lt;/code&gt; is not working well in my Linux Mint. This is very bad for me becuase I need annotate PDF a lot. However, most of programs should be safe in Linux. People who don't care pdf annotation can just skip this point :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="centos-7"&gt;CentOS 7&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="pros-for-me_2"&gt;Pros for Me*&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since CentOS is based on Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL), I tried this system to experience RHEL. Compared to Ubuntu and Linux Mint, which are very GUI-friendly, CentOS tends to be more enterprise-oriented. I do feel CentOS is very powful for all-purpose configuration. I was given a list of installation options at the beginning of installation process. This list ranges from &lt;em&gt;Minimal Installation&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Server Installation&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Workstation Installation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since program installation process in CentOS needs more terminal configuration comparing to Ubuntu, I was pushed to get more exerise in understanding Unix command and functionality. Although for a beginner it really takes time to solve this problem, I really get a lot in this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="cons-for-me_2"&gt;Cons for Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the pro above pointed out, CentOS needs more configuration in terminal, compare to Ubuntu and Linux Mint. This do cause some trouble for a Linux beginner, for example, me. And some configuration problem is hard to get solution online, because compare to Ubuntu and Linux Mint, CentOS tends to be more Unix-Skill-Oriented, and the community for CentOS is not as large as Ubuntu (But it still has a pretty good community!) &lt;em&gt;So here is a trade. I can get valuable experience by solving a configuration problem in CentOS, but this really costs much more time, comparing to Ubuntu&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CentOS has less similarity with Windows comapre to Ubuntu and Linux Mint. This may affect Window user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CentOS gives you lots of freedom to congifure. This can be view as &lt;em&gt;pros&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;cons&lt;/em&gt;. As a beginner, I'm confused because of it. However, &lt;em&gt;this is definetely great for a Linux expert&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CentOS doesn't have as many official software support as Ubuntu. Some software website has installation file specially for Ubuntu, but not a lot for CentOS. You may need to download tar.gz files then install them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a conclution, as a Linux beginner, all three Linux systems are great for me, and I can learn a lot from using them.
However, considering I have some urgent study plan going on, I finally decided to use Ubuntu to save some time. &lt;em&gt;If you don't worry about time, and really want to learn Linux regardless of hard work, I highly recommend CentOS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll continue to learn Linux/Unix skills using Ubuntu. I may turn to CentOS after I get more skills to reduce time cost. I've already enjoyed working in terminal, and I'm looking forward to know more!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Linux</category><category>Operating System</category><guid>https://pengyin-shan.com/posts/2014/linux-comparation/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Install Ubuntu 14 on External Drive from Windows8 Machine with Node.js, Hexo and Jekyll</title><link>https://pengyin-shan.com/posts/2014/install-ubuntu-on-windows-8-machine/</link><dc:creator>Pengyin(Wendy) Shan</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I was thinking of changing my window 8.1 laptop to a dual boot Liunx PC. After checking out my laptop configuration, I felt it may not be a good idea because since my laptop only has 100GB storage in total. After giving windows 8.1 at least 60G, new system can not get enough space. So I decided to install linux system on a 300G external drive, and let laptop boot from this hard drive when I start it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I followed this article &lt;a href="http://www.everydaylinuxuser.com/2014/05/install-ubuntu-1404-alongside-windows.html"&gt;Install Ubuntu 14.04 alongside Windows 8.1 in 10 easy steps&lt;/a&gt;, posted by &lt;em&gt;Gary Newell&lt;/em&gt;, and had no big trouble in process. However, I want to write this post to record some tips during installation process and configuration for Node.js, Hexo and Jekyll after installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="installation-process"&gt;Installation Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="step-1"&gt;Step 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you need to backup your windows 8.1. Windows requires you using at least &lt;em&gt;16GB&lt;/em&gt; usb for backup. You just need to type "recovery" in start window and Windows will find "Recovery Drive" program for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note during recovery process, the focus on your screen is set to the "cancel" button by default. So if you accidently hid Enter, the recovery process will be cancelled. I learned this becuase my cat step over Enter button twice during this process :-(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have a choice to free recovery partition after back-up finishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may also want to back-up your personal file to a save place&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="step-2"&gt;Step 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create Linux Boot USB. Normally a 4GB usb is fine. I use &lt;a href="http://www.linuxliveusb.com/"&gt;LinuxLive USB Creator&lt;/a&gt;, which is free and very powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="step-3"&gt;Step 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shrink windows parition if you want to install Linux locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note you may not be able to shrink C drive a lot using Disk Management on Windows 8.1 when Window is active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I searched on Google and downloaded &lt;a href="http://www.partitionwizard.com/"&gt;Partition Wizard&lt;/a&gt; to shrink C drive. There is a free "Home Edition" and a demo "Professional Edition". Home edition can not merge partitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may want to format your Linux drive to &lt;em&gt;NTFS&lt;/em&gt; format. But when I installed Ubuntu 14 I was give a chance to re-format it to &lt;code&gt;Ext4&lt;/code&gt; format, so I don't think it is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="step-4"&gt;Step 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to turn off your &lt;code&gt;fast-boot&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;secure boot&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To turn off your fast boot, go to &lt;code&gt;control panel&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;power options&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Choose what the power button does&lt;/code&gt;. In the new window, expand &lt;code&gt;Shutdown Settings&lt;/code&gt; then uncheck &lt;code&gt;Turn on fast startup (recommanded)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To turn off secure boot, you need to first hold &lt;code&gt;shift&lt;/code&gt; button, then restart while holding &lt;code&gt;shift&lt;/code&gt;. You will be lead to a blue screen with a button called &lt;code&gt;Troubleshoot&lt;/code&gt;. Click this button and choose &lt;code&gt;Advanced Options&lt;/code&gt;, then select &lt;code&gt;UEFI Firmeware Settings&lt;/code&gt;. Click &lt;code&gt;resart&lt;/code&gt; button on this page, and your pc will restart and go to BIOS setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIOS may looks differently for different PC. In my dell XPS 12, you can move to Boot menu in BIOS setting, then you can disable secure boot. In the next few step you will setup boot priority from here also. Make sure you click &lt;code&gt;F10&lt;/code&gt; to save setting and restart your pc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="step-5"&gt;Step 5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insert your Linux live USB to your pc. If you want to install Linux on a external drive, insert your external drive also. Start your pc. Re-start pc with &lt;code&gt;shift&lt;/code&gt; key to enter the blue setup scrren in step 4. This time click "Use a device" button, and select the name of your Linux live USB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="step-6"&gt;Step 6&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now your pc should run the Linux system from Live USB. Installation process is different between different systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to install Ubuntu on &lt;em&gt;external drive or select internal drive&lt;/em&gt;, make sure you choose &lt;strong&gt;something else&lt;/strong&gt; in installation manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special for Ubuntu 14: the installation manager will give you a change to choose the drive you want to install to. Usually the internal drive is &lt;code&gt;sda&lt;/code&gt; and external drive is &lt;code&gt;sdb&lt;/code&gt;. The empty drive that you want to install should under one of these two type. &lt;em&gt;You should format this drive to ext4 format and assign&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;as the mount&lt;/em&gt;. If you don't choose &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;, Ubuntu will report a &lt;code&gt;root not found&lt;/code&gt; error. You can format certain drive by clicking &lt;code&gt;change&lt;/code&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may choose to set a small &lt;em&gt;swap&lt;/em&gt; driver based on Ubuntu's recommandation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just need to format this drive to &lt;code&gt;linux-swap&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="step-7"&gt;Step 7&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finish installation, make sure you adjust BIOS boot priority. &lt;code&gt;USB storage&lt;/code&gt; should be have highest priority&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="configuration-process-ubuntu14linux-mint-cinam-example"&gt;Configuration Process: Ubuntu14/Linux Mint Cinam Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="nodejs-hexo-heroku-github"&gt;Node.js &amp;amp; Hexo &amp;amp; Heroku &amp;amp; Github&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Node.js: &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install nodejs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install npm: &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install npm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check version: &lt;code&gt;nodejs -v&lt;/code&gt; | &lt;code&gt;npm -v&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Hexo: &lt;code&gt;sudo npm install hexo -g&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Git: &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download &lt;code&gt;Heroku Toolbel&lt;/code&gt; from Heroku website and install it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clone proejct from Heroku (Please check Heroku website if you need to create project): &lt;code&gt;heroku git:clone -a app_name&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get into your project folder and do &lt;code&gt;sudo npm install&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;em&gt;You may encounter error message for node-sass: node not found. Solution is to do&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install nodejs-legacy&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can test Hexo. Get into project folder and try &lt;code&gt;hexo clean&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;hexo generate&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;hexo server&lt;/code&gt;. They should all works fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To re-add Github &lt;code&gt;origin master&lt;/code&gt; branch, do &lt;code&gt;git remote add origin your_git_repo_address.git&lt;/code&gt;. Please refer Github website if you want to create a new repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check your existing git remote for current folder by doing &lt;code&gt;git remove -v&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ruby-jekyll"&gt;Ruby &amp;amp; Jekyll&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install rvm: &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install curl&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;\curl -L https://get.rvm.io | bash -s stable&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Please check the message in terminal after this process. You may need to download signature&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read message in terminal and run &lt;code&gt;source /home/pshan/.rvm/scripts/rvm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install necessary dependencies: &lt;code&gt;rvm requirements&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Ruby: &lt;code&gt;rvm install ruby&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Ruby: &lt;code&gt;rvm use ruby --default&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use RubyGem: &lt;code&gt;rvm rubygems current&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Jekyll: &lt;code&gt;gem install jekyll&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="java-jdk-eclipse"&gt;Java JDK &amp;amp; Eclipse&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download JDK file from Oracle's website&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd /usr/local&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo tax xzf Path_to_JDK_File&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;export JAVA_HOME=/usr/local/jdk1._x.0xx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;export PATH=$PATH:$JAV_HOME/bin&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dowload &lt;code&gt;Eclipse&lt;/code&gt; from Oracle wbesite and Extract folder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may want to choose &lt;code&gt;window&lt;/code&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;code&gt;preference&lt;/code&gt; to change your default JRE path to your preferred JDK. Ubuntu or LinuxMint use OpenJDK as defautl JDK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add server support, First download and extract tomact from Apache website. Then select &lt;code&gt;File&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;New&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Server&lt;/code&gt;, choose tomcat server in list. You can configure tomcat here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="reference-my-list-of-necessary-apps-on-ubuntu"&gt;Reference: My List of Necessary Apps on Ubuntu&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Okular&lt;/code&gt;: pdf annotation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Chrome&lt;/code&gt; | &lt;code&gt;Firefox&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Dropbox&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/code&gt;: Only Sublime Text &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt; has &lt;code&gt;.deb&lt;/code&gt; version&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;MySQL Server&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;MySQL Workbench&lt;/code&gt;: can be installed by &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Linux</category><category>Operating System</category><guid>https://pengyin-shan.com/posts/2014/install-ubuntu-on-windows-8-machine/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>